# Yuandou Wang

No.174, Shazheng Street, Shapingba District, Chongqing, China (+86)133-6813-1478

HomePage: <a href="https://judiths1618.github.io/homepage/judiths11@outlook.com">https://judiths1618.github.io/homepage/judiths11@outlook.com</a>

## **Position Applied for**

**PhD** 

#### **PROFILE**

Good at mathematical modeling. With great research enthusiasm and ambitions. Master's degree of Engineering in Computer Science and Technology with a concentration in Cloud Computing and Service Computing, Game Theory as well as Reinforcement Learning. Bachelor's degree of Engineering in Computer Science and Technology. Flexible programming skills. Work well with team cooperation.

## **Education Background**

2016.9 – 2019.6, Chongqing University (project 985 and project 211 members ), China

Master's Degree of Engineering, College of Computer Science, majoring in Computer Science and Technology

Graduate Recommendation Project, GPA: 83.7/100

Supervised by Prof. Yunni Xia

2012.9 – 2016.6, Chongqing University (project 985 and project 211 members), China

Bachelor's Degree of Engineering, College of Computer Science, majoring in Computer Science and Technology

GPA: 3.28/4.0, Rank: 22/164

## **Publications**

#### **Conference Paper**

- Yuandou Wang, Jiajia Jiang, Yunni Xia, Quanwang Wu, Xin Luo, Qinsheng Zhu. A Multistage Dynamic Game-Theoretic Approach for Multi-Workflow Scheduling on Heterogeneous Virtual Machines from Multiple Infrastructure-as-a-Service Clouds in 15<sup>th</sup> *International Conference on Services Computing* (SCC 2018) pp137-152, 2018. (CCF-C, EI-indexed)
- Li Zhu, **Yuandou Wang**, Wanbo Zheng, Lei Wu, Ye Yuan, Peng Chen, Yunni Xia. Percentile Performance Analysis of Infrastructure-as-a-Service clouds with task retrials in *IEEE 14<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Networking, Sensing and Control* (IEEE ICNSC) Page(s) 270-274, 2017. (EI-indexed)
- Weiling Li, Lei Wu, Yunni Xia, **Yuandou Wang**, Kunyin Guo,Xin Luo, Mingwei Lin, Wanbo Zheng. On Stochastic Performance and Cost-aware Optimal Capacity Planning of Unreliable Infrastructure-as-a-Service Cloud in *International Conference on Algorithms and Architectures for Parallel Processing* (ICA3PP) pp 644-657, 2016. (CCF-C)
- Xiaoning Sun, Jiangchuan Chen, Yunni Xia, Qiang He, **Yuandou Wang**, Xin Luo, Rongqing Zhang, Wuhong Han, Quanwang Wu. A Fluctuation-Aware Approach for Predictive Web Service Composition in *IEEE International Conference on Services Computing* (IEEE SCC 2018) pp121-128, 2018. (CCF-C, best student paper award)

#### **Journal Paper**

• Yuandou Wang, Hang Liu, Wanbo Zheng, Yunni Xia, Yawen Li, Peng Chen, Kunyin Guo, Hong Xie. Multi-Objective Workflow Scheduling with Deep-Q-Network-based Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning in *IEEE Access* Volume 7, Issue 1, pp 39974-39982, 2019, DOI: 10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2902846. (SCI 2 , Impact Factor: 3.557)

# Yuandou Wang

No.174, Shazheng Street, Shapingba District, Chongqing, China (+86)133-6813-1478

HomePage: <a href="https://judiths1618.github.io/homepage/judiths11@outlook.com">https://judiths1618.github.io/homepage/judiths11@outlook.com</a>

- Lei Wu, **Yuandou Wang**. Scheduling Multi-Workflows Over Heterogeneous Virtual Machines With a Multi-Stage Dynamic Game-Theoretic Approach in *International Journal of Web Services Research* (IJWSR) Volume 15, Issue 4, pp 82-96, 2018. (Factor: 0.667)
- Wanbo Zheng, **Yuandou Wang**, Yunni Xia, Quanwang Wu, Lei Wu, Kunyin Guo, Weiling Li, Xin Luo, Qingsheng Zhu. On Dynamic Performance Estimation of Fault-prone Infrastructure-as-a-Service Clouds in *International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks* (IJDSN) Volume 13, Issue 7, 2017. (Factor: 1.787)
- Weiling Li, Yongbo Wang, **Yuandou Wang**, Yunni Xia, Xin Luo, Quanwang Wu. An Energy-Aware and Under-SLA-Constraints VM Consolidation Strategy Based on the Optimal Matching Method in *International Journal of Web Services Research* (IJWSR) Volume 14, Issue 4, pp 75-89, 2017. (Factor: 0.667)
- Kunyin Guo, Ke Yu, Dan Yang, Lei Wu, **Yuandou Wang**. Performance Estimation of Fault-prone Infrastructure-as-a-Service Cloud Computing Systems and their Cost-aware Optimal Performance Determination in *Mobile Networks and Applications* (MONET) Volume 22, Issue4, pp 662-673, 2017. (Factor: 2.497)
- Qinglan Peng, Mengchu Zhou, Yunni Xia, Wanbo Zheng, **Yuandou Wang**, Yawen Li, Xin Luo, Shuiguang Deng, Peng Chen, Chunrong Wu. Reliability-aware and Deadline-constrained Mobile Service Composition over Opportunistic Networks has been accepted by *IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering* (T-ASE), to be published, 2019. (Factor: 5.224)

## **Professional Experience**

#### Implemented TSA prediction based-on CloudSim

Mar 2017 - Jun 2017

- Stimulated VM Scheduling strategies via TSA prediction based on CloudSim with Java Implemented OneScheduler based-on OpenStack Mar 2016 - Jun 2016
- Simulated parallel requests and dynamically collected online data from OpenStack with Python
- Used the ARMIA model to analyze history datasets for the sake of a better performance

## **Parallel Systems Programming**

Sep 2015 - Nov 2015

- Wrote parallel program using pthreads to efficiently detect the same elements in large data set
- Wrote MPI program for sorting algorithms to simulate collective communication in parallel system

#### Courseware training cloud service platform based on PaaS

Aug 2015 - Sep 2015

• Configured and deployed preliminary environments along with Hadoop, MySQL

#### **Employment recommendation system**

Apr 2015 - May 2015

- Deployed the preliminary environment such as Solr with formatted JSON data on server
- Implemented the web crawler that grabbed the current data from <a href="http://www.zhaopin.com/">http://www.zhaopin.com/</a> with Java solrJ

## Secondhand book trading system

Mar 2015 - Apr 2015

- Co-designed the system and corresponded relational database with UML models and E-R models
- Designed JSON interface functions between Android and server

#### **Awards & Honors**

| <ul> <li>Class A Graduate Scholarship in College of Computer Science</li> </ul>     | Oct 2018 |
|---|----------|
| Outstanding student cadres in Chongqing University                                  | Jan 2018 |
| Class A Graduate Scholarship in College of Computer Science                         | Oct 2016 |
| • 3 <sup>rd</sup> Prize in Chongqing University Smart-Campus App Design Competition | May 2015 |

# Yuandou Wang

No.174, Shazheng Street, Shapingba District, Chongqing, China (+86)133-6813-1478

HomePage: https://judiths1618.github.io/homepage/

judiths11@outlook.com

• Honorable Mention with Interdisciplinary Contest in Modeling

Feb 2015

## **Skills**

Programming Python/R/Latex(Skillful), Excel/Visio/UML/Git(Skillful), Java(Basic), C/C++(Basic), Matlab(Basic), Linux/Unix (Basic)

#### **Patents**

- Kunyin Guo, Xiqiao Lin, Yunni Xia, **Yuandou Wang**, Qingsheng Zhu. The dynamic control device, system and method for the number of new tasks in cloud data center (2014), CN104111875 B, CN201410315765.4.
- Yunni Xia, Kunyin Guo, Xin Luo, Weiling Li, **Yuandou Wang**, Quanwang Wu, Ruilong Yang. A task assignment method considering the performance attenuation of cloud platform hosts (2016). CN 106201847A, CN 201610512166.0.

## **High Marks**

|    | Big Data Analysis and Decision Making                      | 91  |
|----|--|---|
| 92 | Meno Part in the Dialogues of Plato                        | A   |
| 90 | Graduation Practice  | A   |
| 90 | Course Project of Operating System                         | A   |
| A  | Electronic Technology Practice(I)                          | A   |
| 90 | Engineering Mathematical Analysis(II)                      | 91  |
| 93 | Course Project of Computer Organization                    | A   |
| A  | Experiments for Analog electronics(II)                     | A   |
| 91 | Digital Electronics (III)                                  | 91  |
| A  | Signals & Systems(II)                                      | 93  |
| 90 | Specialty Practice   | A   |
| 93 | Environment and Health                                     | 90  |
| A  | Interpretation on Chinese Traditional Culture Classics     | 91  |
| 94 |  |   |
|    | 90<br>90<br>A<br>90<br>93<br>A<br>91<br>A<br>90<br>93<br>A | 90 Graduation Practice  90 Course Project of Operating System  A Electronic Technology Practice(I)  90 Engineering Mathematical Analysis(II)  93 Course Project of Computer Organization  A Experiments for Analog electronics(II)  91 Digital Electronics (III)  A Signals & Systems(II)  90 Specialty Practice  93 Environment and Health  A Interpretation on Chinese Traditional Culture Classics |